gliononline.com 2013-03-08

# Privacy Policy

Privacy Policy
for Online Visitors and Students
Overview                                                                       pseudonyms are used. (The use of pseudonyms involves the replacement
                                                                               of names or other identifiers with substitutes, so that identification of
Laureate Education Inc. (“Laureate”) values the privacy of its current,        individual persons is either impossible or at least rendered considerably
past and prospective students, as well as its alumni and all Laureate Web-     more difficult). If data rendered anonymous becomes no longer anony-
site visitors. This Privacy Policy (“Policy”) is intended to:                  mous (i.e., individual persons are again identifiable), or if pseudonyms
                                                                               are used and the pseudonyms allow identification of individual persons,
1) inform students and visitors of sites owned or operated by Laureate        then this Policy will apply.
    institutions how their Personal Data (as defined below) is collected,
    used, disclosed, transferred and processed;                                Capitalized terms in this Privacy Policy have the following
                                                                               meanings:
2) provide choices with respect to how such Personal Data will be han-
    dled by Laureate;                                                          “Data Subject” means an identified or identifiable natural living person.
                                                                               An identifiable person is one who can be identified, directly or indirectly,
3) confirm the consent of students and visitors of sites owned or operated    in particular by reference to an identification number or to one or more
    by Laureate institutions to the collection, processing and transfer of     factors specific to his physical, psychological, mental, economic, cultural
    Personal Data; and                                                         or social identity. For purposes of this Policy, “Data Subject” means Lau-
                                                                               reate Students and visitors to Laureate Websites.
4) facilitate the transfer of such Personal Data from its affiliates in Swit-
    zerland, the European Union (“EU”) and European Economic Area              “European Affiliate” means a Laureate affiliate located in Switzerland,
    (“EEA”) (collectively, “European Affiliates”) to the United States. For    the EU or the EEA.
    purposes of this Privacy Policy, “Laureate” includes all institutions
    operated by European affiliates as listed on Laureate’s Website, www.      “Student” means any individual that is a prospective, current, past stu-
    laureate.net.                                                              dent or alumni of any Laureate institution who is also a resident of Swit-
                                                                               zerland, the EU or EEA.
Please note that this Website may contain links to other Websites. Natu-
rally, Laureate is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content    “Personal Data” means data that personally identifies a Data Subject or
of such other Websites.                                                        that may be used to personally identify a Data Subject (such as an iden-
                                                                               tification number that identifies a Data Subject). Personal Data includes
This Policy complies with the Safe Harbor Principles as agreed upon be-        data such as an individual’s name, country of birth, marital status, emer-
tween the United States Department of Commerce and the European                gency contact, salary information, terms of employment, job qualifica-
Commission. Consistent with its commitment to protect personal priva-          tions (such as educational degrees earned), address, phone number, e-
cy, Laureate adheres to these Safe Harbor Principles, which can be found       mail address, user ID and password. Personal Data does not include data
at: http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/SHPRINCIPLESFINAL.htm.                    that is encoded or anonymized, or publicly available information that has
                                                                               not been combined with non-public Personal Data.
This Policy applies to, and is limited to, the processing of Personal Data
that Laureate receives in the United States concerning its Students and        “Sensitive Data” means Personal Data that discloses a Data Subject’s
Website visitors who are residents of the EEA, EU or Switzerland (see          medical or health condition, race or ethnicity, political, religious or
definition below).                                                             philosophical affiliations or opinions, sexual orientation or trade union
                                                                               membership, aid granted by social services and/or debt collection pro-
This Policy does not cover data rendered anonymous where individual            ceedings, criminal or administration sanctions.
persons are no longer identifiable, or identifiable only with a dispro-
portionately large expense in time, cost, or labor, or situations in which
1 | Privacy Policy                                                                                                            www.gliononline.com

Collection and Use of Personal Data                                          Consent to Disclosures/Onward Transfers of Personal Data
Laureate may receive Personal Data concerning Students:                      For the proper administration of Laureate activities and in order to allow
                                                                             Laureate to fully provide you with the various services contained therein,
1) directly from the Student,                                               you hereby expressly permit Laureate to collect, maintain and process
                                                                             any of your Personal Data, or a part thereof, including without limita-
2) from a European Affiliate or                                             tion, any information protected by the Dutch Data Protection Act, the
                                                                             European Union Directive on the protection of individuals with regard
3) through other means, such as provided by other Websites requested by     to the processing of personal data and the free movement thereof, the
    the individual to be provided to Laureate.                               Swiss Federal Act on Data Protection, or by any other applicable legisla-
                                                                             tion, in any computer network as Laureate deems appropriate. For these
Laureate systems are not set up to automatically or without the express      purposes, you further expressly permit Laureate to transfer such data, or
knowledge of the Student or Website visitor track, collect or distribute     a part thereof, to any computer network(s), including without limitation
Personal Data or Sensitive Data about a Laureate Student or Website          that of any Laureate institution of higher education, that of Laureate rep-
visitor. Our systems do recognize the home server of Students or Web         resentatives worldwide, in the Netherlands, the United Kingdom, Swit-
visitors, but not email addresses. For example, our computer servers can     zerland, the USA or any other country as Laureate deems appropriate to
tell which Internet Service Provider Students or Website visitors of our     provide you services. You understand that the level of data protection in
Websites use, and the IP addresses associated with Students or Website       countries outside the European Union or Switzerland may not be equal
visitors’ computers. But our computer servers do not track names, ad-        to the level of data protection under EU or EAA law and Swiss law and
dresses or other information that would allow us to identify particular      that Laureate will take adequate measures to ensure an adequate level of
Students or Website visitors to our sites. The non-personal information      protection of the Personal Data during and after the transfer.
collected by our servers is used for internal purposes only (such as to
ensure the smooth functioning of the Laureate Websites and efficient de-     Laureate discloses Student’s Personal Data only to those who reasonably
livery of content on the sites, for example knowledge of the Web browser     need to know such data for a legitimate business purpose and those third
used allows content to be displayed in the manner best suited for that       parties must abide by confidentiality obligations. Unless Laureate has
Web browser) by Laureate technical support staff.                            a Data Subject’s consent, Laureate will only disclose Student’s Personal
                                                                             Data to third parties for the purpose of performing tasks on Laureate’s
In addition, Laureate servers track information about visits to our Web-     behalf when such third parties either:
sites. For example, we compile statistics that show the daily number of
visitors to our sites, the daily requests we receive for particular files on (a) comply with the Safe Harbor principles or use another data transfer
our sites and what countries those requests come from. These aggregated           mechanism permitted by the EU Data Protection Directive or, as ap-
statistics are used internally to provide better services to our clients and      plicable, the Swiss Federal Act on Data Protection; or
may also be provided to others, but again, the statistics contain no Per-
sonal Data and cannot be used to discern such information.                   (b) agree to provide adequate protections for the Data Subject’s privacy
                                                                                  interests that are no less protective than those set out in this Privacy
Subject to the below consent of the Data Subject, Laureate uses Student           Policy and agree to use such Data Subject’s Personal Data only for
Personal Data for business purposes, including without limitation:                the purposes for which the third party has been engaged by Laureate.
(i)	managing Student on-line experiences;                                   If Laureate learns that one of its data processors/service providers is us-
                                                                             ing or disclosing Personal Data in a manner contrary to this Policy, Lau-
(ii)	enrollment into an institution;                                        reate will take necessary steps to prevent or stop the use or disclosure.
(iii) enrollment in specific courses;                                        Sensitive Data
(iv) recording and reporting grades;                                         Except as stated otherwise herein, Laureate does not disclose Sensitive
                                                                             Data to third parties. Further, Laureate does not use Sensitive Data for
(v)	managing the process for prospective students through enrollment        any purpose other than
        and admission;
                                                                             (i)	for the purpose for which it was originally provided by the Student,
(vii)	managing alumni;
                                                                             (ii)	for a purpose later expressly consented to by the Student, or
(viii)	marketing purposes, as permitted under applicable local law or
        regulations; and                                                     (iii) for an exception expressly noted below.
(ix)	for other business-related purposes permitted and/or required un-
        der applicable local law or regulations.
Choice
Laureate respects your right to privacy. When a Laureate affiliate con-
tacts you for marketing purposes, you will be advised of how to remove
your name from receiving any further materials. You may also remove
yourself at any time by following the links provided on each institution’s
privacy policy page which will provide you with the contact information
for that institution or instructions on how to remove your name from
receiving any further materials from that institution.
2 | Privacy Policy                                                                                                           www.gliononline.com

You expressly agree that Laureate may use or disclose Sensitive Data (or      Changes to this Policy
other Personal Data) without prior express consent where such disclo-
sure or use:                                                                  This Policy may be amended from time to time, consistent with any
                                                                              changes in the Safe Harbor Principles and/or Laureate business practices.
(a)	is in the vital interests of the Student, Website visitor or another     Appropriate public notice will be given in the event of such amendments.
       person;
                                                                              Questions or Complaints
(b)    is necessary for the establishment of legal claims or defenses;
                                                                              Students and site visitors may contact Laureate with questions or com-
(c)	is required to provide medical care or diagnosis;                        plaints concerning this Privacy Policy at the following address:
(d)    is necessary to carry out Laureate’s obligations;                      Jorge Elguera
                                                                              Chief Innovation and Information Officer
(e)	is data manifestly made public by the Data Subject; or                   650 S. Exeter Street, 8th Floor
                                                                              Baltimore, MD 21202
(f)    as otherwise required or permitted by law.                             +01 (410) 843-8336
                                                                               jorge.elguera@laureate.net
Confidentiality and Security of Personal Data
                                                                              Oversight
Laureate maintains reasonable physical, administrative and technical
safeguards designed to secure Data Subjects’ Personal Data and Sensi-         Laureate’s privacy practices are self-certified as defined in the U.S. De-
tive Data, and to prevent unauthorized access to such information. For        partment of Commerce Safe Harbor Program. For more information
example, all Student communication and files in digital format are stored     about the Safe Harbor Program, please go to www.export.gov/safeharbor
on a secure network, accessible only by approved staff. All critical sys-
tems and servers are separately housed within Laureate’s secure facili-       Enforcement and Dispute Resolution
ties and are accessible only by authorized personnel. Our information
security is managed internally and meets industry standards for secure        Laureate periodically verifies that the Policy is accurate, comprehensive
networks. Laureate takes precautions to protect personal information          for the information intended to be covered, and conforms to the EU
from loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and        Safe Harbor Principles and the Swiss Federal Act on Data Protection.
destruction. Laureate’s physical premises are protected with a security       We encourage interested persons to raise any concerns with us using the
guard and all off-hour entry is logged through an access control system.      contact information below. Laureate will investigate and attempt to re-
Laureate periodically performs network backups. While our backup files        solve complaints and disputes regarding use and disclosure of personal
are stored offsite, they are handled by authorized personnel only.            information in accordance with the principles contained in this Policy.
                                                                              With respect to any complaints related to this Policy that cannot be re-
Right to Access, Change or Delete Personal Data                               solved through our internal process, we agree to participate in the dis-
                                                                              pute resolution procedures with the European Data Protection Authori-
Upon reasonable request and to the extent the request does not compro-        ties (“DPA”) to resolve disputes pursuant to the Safe Harbor Principles.
mise the protections set forth in this Privacy Policy, Laureate and any       In the event that a dispute is submitted to one of the DPAs, we will co-
of its institutions allows Data Subjects reasonable access to their Per-      operate with such DPA in the investigation and resolution of complaints
sonal Data, including any Sensitive Data that Laureate may maintain.          brought under this policy. If we or such DPA conclude that we did not
Individuals have the right to receive confirmation from Laureate and any      comply with the Policy, we will take appropriate steps to address any
of its institutions about the data relating to them that Laureate or any of   adverse effects and assure future compliance.
its institutions stores in its files, and may request that Laureate or any of
its institutions correct, amend, or delete that information when it is inac-  Laureate retains sole and absolute discretionary authority to resolve all
curate. Students should direct any such request following the procedure       questions relating to the administration, interpretation and application
provided by each institution for changes to any Personal Data. Students       of this Policy. This authority includes interpreting the terms of this Poli-
or Website visitors may also direct any questions or requests for changes     cy, including any disputed or doubtful terms.
to the contact listed below.
Laureate and any of its institutions will endeavor to respond in a timely
manner to all reasonable written requests to view, modify or delete Per-
sonal Data.
Data Integrity
Students and site visitors are responsible for the accuracy of the data they
provide to Laureate. Laureate will use reasonable efforts to maintain the
accuracy and integrity of any Personal Data it receives and update it as
appropriate.
Laureate does not, as a matter of business practices, maintain Personal
Data longer than necessary for the purposes stated, unless otherwise
agreed to by the Student or site visitor.
3 | Privacy Policy                                                                                                          www.gliononline.com
